Inventory of the Nikolaĭ Vsevolodovich Shinkarenko memoirs
Hoover Institution Archives
Nikolaĭ Vsevolodovich Shinkarenko memoirs
1913-1961
68020
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes (1.6 linear feet)
The Nikolaĭ Vsevolodovich Shinkarenko memoirs contain material relating to Russian cavalry operations in World War I, White Russian military operations in the Russian Civil War, Spanish military operations in Africa, and Francoist military operations in the Spanish Civil War. Includes copies of letters and photographs.
Shinkarenko, Nikolaĭ Vsevolodovich, 1890-1968.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1968.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Russian Imperial Army officer; brigadier general of cavalry, White Russian Army; Spanish Foreign Legion officer.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Nikolaĭ Vsevolodovich Shinkarenko memoirs contain material relating to Russian cavalry operations in World War I, White Russian military operations in the Russian Civil War, Spanish military operations in Africa, and Francoist military operations in the Spanish Civil War. Includes copies of letters and photographs.
Russia. Armii͡a--Officers.; Spain. Ejército.; World War, 1914-1918--Russia.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Spain--Colonies.; Spain--History--Civil War, 1936-1939.
- Correspondence, 1914-1937 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Memoir Volumes, 1921-1961
  - Table of contents, undated (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Part I, undated (Box-folder 1: 3-6)
  - Part II, 1957 (Box-folder 1: 7, Box-folder 2: 1-3)
  - Part III, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 4-6)
  - Part IV, 1929-1941 (Box-folder 3: 1-3)
  - Part V, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 3: 4-6, Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Supplement, 1956 (Box-folder 4: 2-5)
- Photographs, 1913-1914 (Box-folder 4: 6-13)